if you need a database for your project
then mongodb is a great choice but it
can be difficult to learn at first so in
this video i'm going to break down every
important concept of mongodb so you can
become an expert by the end of the video
and we're going to cover everything from
the basics of create read update delete
all the way to more advanced queries and
advanced updates so make sure you stick
around to the end of the video
[Music]
welcome back to web dev simplified my
name is kyle and my job is to simplify
the web for you so you can start
building your dream project sooner and
in this video we're going to be doing a
mongodb crash course now to follow along
in this video you're first going to need
to install mongodb i'm going to have
links to these pages in the description
below but essentially go to this page
scroll down find your operating system
and then just install the community
edition of mongodb walk through the
install step and that'll be all you need
to do and then once you have mongodb
installed you're gonna need to install
sh this is the shell that you can
work with to actually access and read
database queries so just come down here
to your operating system click on it and
then follow the steps down below it's
pretty straightforward and once you have
that done you can open up a terminal
which i just have here and you can type
in the command sh that's going to
open up that shell and as you can see it
says we're using mongodb version 5. we
have version 1 of sh that's
because this version 5 of mongodb and
sh are very new they came out just
a few weeks ago so this is going to be
the most up-to-date information you can
find now the first set of commands i
want to talk about are just basic
commands that allow you to actually use
the sh terminal and be able to
create and view different databases and
first you'll see that we have the word
test written here that's essentially the
name of the database that we're
currently using this is just the default
database you get started in it's a test
database it has no data and it doesn't
really exist yet until you create data
in order to view your databases you need
to type in show space dbs and dbs just
stands for databases and you'll see here
we have an admin an appdb a config and a
local when you type this in you should
see just admin config and local and you
won't see this appdb that's because i
created this appdb already and it has
some data already in it now if you want
to be able to access and use a database
just type in use followed by the name of
the database you want to use so in our
example we could say appdb to use the
appdb database or we could create a
brand new name right here if we wanted
to and that's going to create a new
database and put us inside of that so
for our case let's just jump into this
appdb database now since that exists i
click use you can see it says switch to
that database and now it says appdb
instead of test now in order to view
what collections we have in that
database we can just type in show
collections and in mongodb there's
essentially two different things you
have databases which are just like
databases and sql and then you have
collections and collections are like
tables inside of a database if you're
familiar with sql it's just where you
store your data and you can call them
whatever you want so we have a user's
collection inside of this database now
obviously we don't really want to use
this database because it's already
pre-built so i'm going to show you how
you can actually delete an entire
database and to do that you just type in
db dot drop database and call it like
it's a function the nice thing about
mongodb is if you're familiar with
javascript a lot of the syntax in
mongodb is very similar to javascript
you're calling functions and passing
them parameters so if we type this you
can see it says ok one and it dropped
appdb and now if we click show dbs here
and type that in you can see that that
appdb no longer exists and also if we
want to clear our screen we can type in
cls it's going to clear our screen
completely and put us back at the top
this is just great if you have a bunch
of junk on your screen one thing you'll
notice though is we're still in appdb
and that's because monkodb is kind of
interesting compared to other things
like sql and that's that you don't
actually need to ever create a table you
don't need to create database users you
don't need to create collections that's
because whenever you try to access
something if it doesn't exist yet and
you try to put data in it it'll just
automatically create itself so if we try
to add data to this app db that we're
currently inside of it'll now recreate
that database because as you can see if
we do show dbs we have no databases but
now we can actually try to add something
to this database and it'll recreate that
database now the last command i want to
show you before we get into creating
data is just the exit command you type
that in and it exits you out of the
terminal and we can come back in here
with sh and re-enter that terminal
so that's just one really simple command
that you can use to exit out of the
terminal so now that we're in the
terminal i just want to type in use
appdb and it's going to use that app
database you can call this whatever you
want it really does not matter and
that's just because if we type in
showdbs again you'll see this database
doesn't exist yet we're just going to be
using it and then adding data to it
which will automatically create that
database for us now to access the
current database you're inside of you
just type db that gives you the current
database and this has a bunch of
functions essentially on it so we can
say db dot and we can say the name of a
collection so a collection like i said
is a table so we can call this whatever
we want we're going to call ours users
where we're going to store all of our
user data and then to insert into this
table you just type in dot insert one
and this allows us to insert one single
record inside of this user's collection
and this insert one is a function and
inside this function all you do is you
just want to pass it an object and this
object is just a javascript object
essentially it's like json formatted so
what we want to do for our object let's
just pass in a name here and the name is
going to be john and we hit enter and
you can see it says true and it inserted
that with this id right here so now if
we wanted to be able to see this
information we can just say db.users to
access the collection and we can call
the find method the find method just
gets every single thing inside of the
database and as you can see we have an
array with one object that object has a
unique id that's automatically generated
and then it has the name of john now
this underscore id is something that's
automatically generated by mongodb every
time you insert a record so that's
really nice you don't have to worry
about generating unique ids it just does
it for you also something interesting
about mongodb that you may have noticed
is we didn't have to define any columns
we didn't define any schema we just said
insert this json object that has a name
and the name is john there's no schemas
there's no columns that you have to
worry about in mongodb and instead you
worry about things called documents
essentially every single object you
store inside of a database in mongodb is
called a document and documents live in
collections and collections live inside
of databases so we have our appdb which
is our database users is our collection
and this john document right here that
is our document inside of our users
collection and because there is no
schema it means you can actually add
anything you want inside of your
collections and they don't all have to
have the same columns or the same fields
so we could come in here and we could
say db.users
insert one
oops insert one and we want to insert a
brand new user and this user is going to
have a name
and we're going to give them the name of
sally so so far this is exactly the same
as john it has just the name field but
we're going to add additional
information for example we're going to
put an age in here and we're going to
say that they are 19 as well and then
we're going to add in more information
we're going to add an address and one
really nice thing about mongodb is you
can actually nest things inside of it
because just like json you can put
objects inside of objects so we're going
to nest an address object inside of our
user right here so we're going to say
the address has a street
and this street is just going to be 987
north street
and then we're going to close off that
object and we're also going to put an
array of hobbies inside here so let's
put an array of hobbies and we're just
going to put one hobby inside of here
which is running
and if we just close this off and run
this you can see acknowledge true and
inserted that user and if we do
db.users.find
you can now see we have john up here is
our first object and then we have sally
down here which has the name sally age
19 the address which has the street
inside of it and then our array of
hobbies so with mongodb we don't have to
have all of the documents inside of our
collection share the same fields and
also we can nest things such as nesting
an address inside a user or nesting an
array of hobbies inside of here which is
something that's pretty much impossible
or very difficult to do in sql let me
just clear my screen real quick and get
back to the top and i want to talk about
how you can insert multiple records at
once so if we go db.users there's
another function called insert
many and this is just like insert one
but it takes an array of objects instead
so we could say that we're going to have
a name here of
jill and then we're also going to just
close that off and pass in another
person which has a name of mike
so now essentially we're passing an
array to this insert menu which has one
object here of jill and one object of
mic we hit enter you can see it inserted
both of those if we do dbusers.find
you can see that we now have jill and
mike at the bottom now in order to
populate our database with a little bit
more information i'm just going to do
another db.users.insertmany
i'm actually just going to copy over a
bit of information just a few different
objects so that way we don't have to
manually type these in and essentially
i'm just inserting a user here that is
myself kyle and then we have another
billy down here so if i hit enter and
just do db or first i'll clear and then
do db.users.find
oops
and as you can see if we type in an
error it's really nice they have really
good error handling so it tells you hey
you just messed up your error right
there so now you can see we inserted
this user kyle which has age 26 hobbies
of weightlifting and bowling and then we
added an address same thing here billy
has swimming bowling age 41 and another
address this is just so when we do more
complex queries we can actually query in
all these different pieces of
information for our database now
speaking of querying that's the very
next thing i want to do how do you read
information from your database well we
figured out that users has a find method
and this find method just gets every
single thing from the database as we can
see but what we can do is actually
additional information on top of that so
we could say db.users.find
and then we could call additional
message after this for example if we
wanted to sort things or we wanted to
limit so we could say you know what
limit me to only two results and now you
can see we're getting the first two
results in the database but what if we
wanted to sort them by for example names
so we wanted to get them in alphabetical
order well we could come in here we
could say db.users
dot find and then we can just say sort
and for sort this takes an object and
this object has a key which is the thing
you want to sort by so for example we
want to sort by name and then you pass
it either one or you pass it negative
one depending on the order that you want
to sort in so let's just pass in one at
first and then we're going to limit this
as well
to 2 and as we hit enter you can see we
get billy first and then jill and that's
going in alphabetical order now if we
pass in negative 1 it's going to do the
reverse order so now you can see we get
sally first and then mike next and
that's because it's going in reverse
alphabetical order and a really nice
thing that we can do is we can actually
sort by multiple fields at once so if we
just come in here we wanted to sort by
name and then we wanted to sort by age
for example so let's do age first
and we're going to do that in order and
then name second in reverse order now
you can see that we're getting mike and
john showing up here and that's just
because they don't have an age so
they're showing up at the very beginning
we change our age here to negative one
you can see that now it's sorting in age
reverse order first so it's going 41 and
then 26 and if we had two people with
the same age then it would also sort
them by name in reverse order as well
and the last thing i want to talk about
of these sorting type methods is skip
and skip just allows you to skip the
first few things so let's say
db.users.find and we're going to limit
this to just two you can see we get john
and then sally but if we put in a little
skip here let's just say we want to skip
one that's going to skip the first entry
so now we start with sally and then we
also get jill as well which comes after
sally now these message are great but
really what we want to do is build a
query on different fields so we want to
do essentially where queries if you're
familiar with sql to do that we just
pass a parameter to our find method so
we're going to say db.users.find and
here we just pass an object to find and
this can get really complex or be pretty
simple but the main thing you have to
worry about is you want to pass in the
thing that you want to find by let's
just do name and then you can pass it a
value so let's just say kyle what this
query does is says hey find everyone
where the name is equal to kyle and as
you can see we get just one object where
the name is equal to kyle that makes
sense we can also query by additional
things you know we could come in here we
could say age and we wanted the age to
be for example 26 and now you can see we
get kyle again because he has the age of
26 but it's important to note this age
is a number so if i tried to query where
the age is a string of 26 we get nothing
back and that's because the age is a
number again so it's only going to match
where the age is equal to this as a
number not as a string
now also if you're familiar with sql
you're probably familiar with the select
syntax where you can select just a
single row or a single column from the
database so i want to get just the name
or just the age or the name and the age
but not the hobbies well we can actually
do that as well we can say db.users.find
and we're just going to find where the
name
here
is equal to kyle
and then what we need to do is pass a
second parameter which again is an
object to find and this object here
tells us what parameters we want to get
so let's say we want to get the name
field we're just going to pass a 1 to
that we pass a 1 here that's saying hey
we want to get this field so let's get
the name and the age and that's the only
thing is going to be returned as you can
see we get name of kyle age 26 but the
hobbies in the address are not returned
you also notice the id is returned
automatically if you don't want the id
be returned just put underscore id and
then set this to zero that's saying hey
don't get me the id field now as you can
see we get just the name and age without
the id
also if we wanted to come in here and we
said hey you know i want to get all the
fields except for the age i don't care
about the age if we just put age zero
here and nothing else it's going to say
hey get all the fields but don't get age
so as you can see we get name hobbies
address and id but the age field is left
out so you can either use ones to say
you want to select only these fields or
you can use a 0 and say hey select all
the fields except for this and this is a
pretty straightforward where clause
we're saying where name equals this but
what if we wanted to do something a bit
more complex well that's where we can do
complex queries instead so let's say
db.users.find
and again we're going to pass this in
object and inside this object we're
going to say hey we want to query on the
name field but in order to do a complex
query what we need to do is put again
another set of an object and this object
is going to contain all the information
for the complex query and inside of
mongodb pretty much every single complex
query is going to start with a dollar
sign and then you're going to denote
what you want to do so if we want to
check for equality just like we were
doing before you could say dollar sign
eq and then we can pass in here that we
want the value to be sally
and what this is saying is hey get me
where the name is equal to sally just
like we were doing before and as you can
see we get sally returned but we could
also do something else for example we
could do not equal and this is going to
get us everything that is not equal to
sally so now if we hit enter and i make
sure to change this to n e instead of n
eq you're gonna see we get all of the
users returned except for the ones where
the name is equal to sally now there's a
bunch of these different types of
complex queries so i want to cover as
many of them as i can as quickly as
possible so we'll say db.users.find
and we're going to find here on the age
property because that allows us to do a
lot of these and again we want to make
sure that we have an object and this
object we're going to do greater than so
dollar sign greater than and we're going
to say everything that has an age
greater than 13 and as you can see we
get only the users that have an age
greater than 13. we could also do
greater than or equal to which is gte so
if we did like 19 for example you can
see greater than or equal to 19 returns
19. we can do less than or equal to as
you can see only sally's return because
she's the only one with an h less than
or equal to 19. and if we do less than
we get nothing returned because nothing
has an age less than 19. now also some
more queries that we can do we just come
in here db.users.find
and let's say that we want a query on
name this time and we want to say where
the name is equal to one of two values
we can use dollar sign in and that
essentially says hey if the name is in
this list of names then return it so we
can pass it an array and we can say kyle
and we can say sally and this just says
hey is the name kyle or is it sally if
so return it and as you can see we get
kyle and we get sally being returned we
can also do essentially the opposite of
n by saying not in by just putting an n
in front of this now it gets us all the
users that don't have a name that's
either kyle or selly and as you can see
kyle and sally are the only ones left
out of this list another query that's
really important that you're probably
going to want to do we'll just say
db.users.find
we want to find by age and we want to
check to see hey which ones have an age
that exists because as you know some of
our documents don't actually have an h
so to check for exist we just do dollar
sign exist and we say true and this is
going to return only the objects that
have an age on them as you can see all
three of these objects have an age if we
pass false to exist now it's only going
to return to us the objects that don't
have an age so we can check whether or
not there is an age or there isn't an
age and this is going to return only
things that don't include the key one
thing to note though is this is only
going to check to see if the key exists
if we have an object for example a name
here of john and the age is set to null
exist true is going to return the age
that has null because it only checks to
see if the key actually exists on the
user and not if the value exists i can
really easily show that by just saying
db.users.insert1
and we're going to insert something that
has an age that is set to null and a
name which is just going to be
bill
and if we just close that off and i do
that check where exist is true you can
see even though the age is null it still
returns when we check for exist true up
here now the next couple queries i want
to talk about are going to be pretty
complex queries when you want to combine
together multiple queries so say
db.users.find
we're going to do a find here on age and
again we're going to wrap this inside of
an object in this object we want to
check to see when the age is going to be
less than a certain value and greater
than a certain value so we can say gte
so we want to check is it greater than
or equal to the value of 20 and we want
to say hey which check also less than or
equal to
of 40. we hit enter and you can see we
get all the users that have an age
greater than 20 and less than or equal
to 40. and this way this works is if you
pass an object to a field essentially it
does all of these as an and query so
it's going to say okay where the age is
greater than or equal to 20 and it is
less than or equal to 40 do this query
if we combine additional things on this
for example we pass a name here we say
the name must equal sally now it's
saying that the age has to be greater
than or equal to 20 less than or equal
to 40 and the name has to be sally we
change this to kyle we'll see that we
actually get one result because this
name is equal to kyle and the age falls
within this range specified so this is
one way where you can do an and query
another way that you can do an and query
though if we just clear our screen here
we say db.users dot find and inside this
find we're going to pass dollar sign and
and when we use this dollar signed and
essentially what we're saying is hey
pretend that we're doing another find
and inside of here we're just combining
all the things inside the and so and
takes an array and in this array we can
just do what we did before in a fine so
we can say you know we'll do age which
is equal to exactly 26 and we'll come in
here and we're going to say
name
oops make sure this is an object
is going to be equal to kyle
make sure i close this off so now you
can see we passed in dollar sign and
which takes an array and this array has
an age of 26 and a name kyle being
passed in so it's combining both of
these together and as you can see we get
kyle being returned generally you don't
really need to use this dollar sign and
very much and that's just because you
already can do ands almost every other
way by just putting them all inside of
one query but one thing that you do need
is ors if you want to do an or you're
going to need to use the dollar sign or
syntax so let's say the age here is
going to be
whoops less than
or equal to 26
or the name is going to be kyle and
actually let's make this less than or
equal to 20. there we go so now we're
saying hey i want to see where the age
is less than or equal to 20 or the name
is kyle and of course we're getting an
error that's just because i need to make
sure here i close off this object now
you can see we're getting sally returned
because her age is less than 20 and
we're getting kyle returned because the
name is equal to kyle so the or syntax
is really important because there's no
other way to do or unless you use the
dollar sign or here another thing you
can really easily do if we just say
db.users.find
is if you want to do a not query so
let's say that we want to check here
when the age is going to be less than or
equal to 20
and let's say we actually want it to be
not less than or equal to 20. well what
you can do is you can just create
another object and put the not inside of
it and you just pass an object to not
and essentially what not does is it just
negates everything that's inside of it
so now we hit enter and i make sure that
i add in the correct number of curly
brackets you can see we're getting all
of the users where the age is not less
than or equal to 20. so we're getting
all the users where the age is greater
than 20 but we're also getting all the
users where there is no age defined as
you can see here these users have no age
and this one has an age of null while if
we for example did something like
greater than
20 which is essentially the same thing
but we remove this knot and hit enter
and i make sure that i have the object
here
you can see now we're only getting users
that have an age defined so that's one
thing that knot can kind of do
differently so if you do a knot it'll
actually return all the things that
don't have ages in this case really for
the most part though you don't ever
really need to use not because less than
greater than not equal to equal they
already all have the not version but
it's good to know that it exists now the
last complex one of these queries i need
to talk about requires me to add a
little bit additional data to our
database so we'll say db.users.insert
many
inside of here i'm just going to be
inserting users that have a balance
object as well as a debt object so if we
hit enter you can see we inserted these
two users and what i want to do is i
want to find the users where their debt
is greater than their balance
essentially they're in debt so to do
that we can say db.users
dot find and in order to compare two
different properties on an object what
we need to do is we need to use the
dollar sign expr that stands for
expression and inside of here you can
run a query that compares two different
things so let's say that we want to do a
greater than query we want to see where
the debt is greater than the balance so
we can say greater than and inside of
here we're going to pass it in array and
this is going to say hey where the debt
column is greater than the balance
column so the first thing we passed this
array is going to be the first column we
want to check to see if it's greater
than the second column we hit enter and
i make sure that i close everything off
you'll see now we're actually getting
all of our results being returned and
you're probably wondering why is this
the reason is is because if you want to
actually access a column instead of a
specific value you need to put a dollar
sign in front so now you can see we have
dollar signed debt and dollar signed
balance now when i hit enter i only get
the object being returned that has a
debt of 200 and a balance of 100 so the
debt is greater than the balance so if
you're going to be using columns just
make sure you use that dollar sign
syntax in order to do that now if we
just clear this out i want to talk about
a few additional find methods that are
just going to be continuations on what
we've already talked about so we can say
db.users.find and if we want to find
based on a nested field so example we
have address.street
that we want to query on well in order
to make this query we just wrap this
address dot street name in quotes and we
have an address object and inside it has
a street property so you can say address
dot street just like you're going to be
accessing this with javascript and then
we can use all the additional queries we
talked about so we get set to a specific
value for example main street like this
i close that off you can see we get the
user that has 123 main street as their
street or you know we could combine this
with you know less than equal to is
greater than we could do all that
additional stuff passing it in just like
this this address dot street is just
like any other column name also
something that we can do is we can do a
find one so that allows us to just find
one object that matches the query so
let's just do here a find one and we're
going to pass it in age and we're going
to say where the age here is less than
or equal to
40. for example close this off now you
can see it just found the first user
that has an age less than or equal to
40. so if you did some kind of sorting
for example you could find the first
user that has an h less than or equal to
40. that's what find one is going to do
and then also we have the ability to
count so instead of find one we could
change this to count documents now we
hit enter and you can see there are two
people in our database that have an age
less than or equal to 40. now that right
there pretty much covers everything you
need to know about querying data so next
we want to talk about updating data
which is of course an incredibly
important part of any database so in
order to update a field we just want to
say db.users and we have a method called
update1 and this allows us to update to
just the very first thing just like find
one this is going to be the same thing
but for updating one object and the
first parameter to update one is just
going to be the thing we want to filter
on this is the exact same thing that you
passed to find all the things we talked
about inside a dot find work for this
update one so let's say we want to get
the user where the age is 26 this is the
user with the name of kyle so where the
name is 26 we want to update them and
then we can pass in here all the update
things we want to do and this is kind of
confusing for most people because you
would think okay we'll just say you know
age is going to be 27 and that's going
to work right but this is actually going
to throw an error as you can see update
document requires atomic operators and
that's because they require dollar sign
operators so in order to do a set
operation where you want to set a field
for example we want to update our age to
27 you need to use dollar sign set and
then pass it the things you want to
update so in our case we want to update
our age to 27. hit enter you can see it
updated and then if we do a
db.users.find
one and we're just going to do where the
age is now 27
you can see we got that user kyle which
has an age of 27. and up here if usually
if you're going to be doing an update
you're going to want to update based on
the id so we could say where the id is
equal to and we'll just copy this id
right here and paste that in and now we
can set for example
the name to new
name hit enter and we're going to do a
find based on that id as well so we'll
say underscore id is equal to the id we
have here now you can see the name has
been updated to new name now there's a
few other things you can do for updating
so we'll say
db.users.update 1 we're going to pass in
that underscore id again because we want
to get just that one user and instead of
doing a set here i'm going to do an
increment so i can actually increment
the value of a number so i want to
increment our age property by let's say
3. so now we're going to go from 27 to
30. and if i just close this off hit
enter and i find that user so we can say
db users find one you can see now their
age is 30 has incremented it by 3.
another really cool thing that we can do
with update 1 instead of increment is we
can rename a column so i want to rename
let's say the name column i want to
rename it to first name just like that
if i make sure here that i spell rename
properly hit enter and now i find that
user you can see that their name
property has been renamed to first name
another thing we can do is unset a
property so if we just say
we're going to do
dbusers.update1 and instead of rename
here we're going to do unset and i want
to unset the property here which is
going to be age so we're just going to
say age in order to make sure we do this
properly we actually need to pass this
in as an object and just set the value
to anything it really doesn't matter
we'll just do an empty string so now
we're unsetting the age property we're
just removing it completely so if i just
make sure i have enough closing
parenthesis here
and i find that user you can now see we
completely removed the age property it
didn't set it to null it completely
removed it from the object another thing
that we can do is actually add two
arrays so if we just come back to this
update here we can say that we want to
push a value into our array and inside
of here we just want to say our array is
going to be called hobbies because
that's the array right here we want to
push to this hobby's array and we want
to push in the value of let's say
swimming for example
we just hit all those parentheses make
sure they're closed off hit enter now if
we find that user you can see we added
swimming to the end of the array we can
also do essentially the opposite of
removing so if we just get that update
again instead of push we can say pull
and let's say that we wanted to pull
from here something like bowling so
we'll just type in bowling hit enter and
now if we find that user you can see we
removed boeing from the list and the
interesting thing about this push and
this poll is that it takes the same
queries as find one so if we had like an
array of numbers we could say hey remove
everything less than or equal to the
value of three and it's going to remove
all of those so again all of those
queries that we talked about in find
they work all over the place in tv
now the next thing i want to talk about
is updating many users at once so we can
just say update many and this is going
to update everything that matches a
specific query so let's say we want to
get them where the address exists so
we're just going to say dollar sign
exists
we're going to set that to true so every
single thing that has an address is
going to be matched by this query and
all we want to do is just unset the
address so we're going to remove the
address from everything
i'm just going to say address
and just put an empty quote inside of
here
close this off hit enter you can see
we've updated three different things and
now if we do a dbi users.find to get
everything you'll notice none of our
users have an address because we got all
the users that had an address and we
removed that address field so that's
what update menu allows us to do and
then finally we have replace which is
kind of interesting so let's just say
db.users.replace1
and this is how we replace one single
object let me just actually clear this
out so we'll say db.users.replace1
and replace one takes the same exact
filter so we can say age is equal to 30.
that's the user that has the name kyle
and then here we just pass it a new
object so let's just say the name here
is going to be equal to
john
and now if i hit enter on this if i just
close this off hit enter you can see it
worked and now i can say db.users.find
we can say name is equal to john
close this off and you'll see we get
this user here what happened is we found
the user with the age of 30 and then
replaced that entire object with
whatever we passed in here so since we
only passed a name of john that's the
only thing that was saved to that user
so replace essentially takes everything
at that location deletes it and then
replaces it with what we pass in to
replace
generally 99.9 of the time you're going
to want to use update instead of replace
because you don't want to actually
replace an entire object you just want
to update a few fields at a time now
that's everything that we need to know
about updating so let's move on to
deleting so we can just say db.users and
we can do delete one to delete one user
and it takes the same exact thing as
find so we could say here name is equal
to
john to delete that user we just added
you can see it deleted one user
db.users.find
where the name is equal to john
and now you're going to see nothing gets
returned because we just deleted that
user we can also do a delete menu so
db.users.delete
many and here we're going to delete
everything that has no age so we're
going to say age
we're going to check for exists so we'll
say dollar sign exist
false this is going to be anything that
doesn't have an age is going to be
deleted you see it says it deleted 5
different thing
and if we say users find you can see now
we only have users that have an age even
if the age is null it just has an age
key on it
and that right there is everything you
need to know about mongodb if you
enjoyed this video i highly recommend
you check out the full cheat sheet on
mongodb i have linked in the description
below and with that said thank you very
much for watching and have a good day